# Bryan Leighton

Full Stack Web Developer

2	an.leigh//@gmail.com
	+49 151 6 874 6342
(	Tel Aviv, Israel

linkedin.com/in/bryan77 in

github.com/bdlb77 🦪

www.bryandl.com

I am a highly motivated person who has profound experience in work under extreme pressure, and great adaptability to any situation that is presented. Having served in a military that is not of my native tongue, while also learning medical terminology and techniques in a foreign language, I have learned that my strength is my ability to persevere through any hardship and realizing that nothing is ever impossible to accomplish.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Web Developer

#### Freelance

10/2018 - Present

- Paul Ziemiak (CDU) Website WordPress
- SVApp Private Mentor and development of personal mobile app project.
- Priicer Automation of electricity meter based on price
- Immigration Works automation of Refugee hiring process in Germany

#### Instructor

#### Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp

07/2018 – Present Israel, Germany

– Instruct in fullstack web development

Contact: Clara Morgeneyer - +49 178 2004 525

# Egoz Special Operations Unit Combat Medic Israel Defense Forces

11/2015 – 05/2018 Israel

- Special Operations Combat Medic First Sergeant
- Active Combat Medic on deployment in hostile zones
- Led First Aid and medical trainings within the Company

# **EDUCATION**

#### Full Stack Web Development

Le Wagon Coding Bootcamp

04/2018 – 06/2018 Tel Aviv, Israel

- HTML/ CSSRuby on RailsPostgreSQL
- **B.A. International Relations and Global Studies** University of Texas at Austin

08/2012 - 05/2015 3.37/4.0

- <del>-</del>
- Middle Eastern SudiesFrenchInternational Security

# **Concentration in European Union studies**

Sciences Po - Exchange

07/2013 – 12/2013 Paris, France

EU Strategic Studies
 U.S. Foreign Policy

### **SKILLS**



#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Forget Me Not (06/2018 − 06/2018) 🗷

- 2-week final project during coding bootcamp. Business networking web app
- http://forgetmenot.network

#### Open Source Contributions

NativeScript (https://docs.nativescript.org)

## **LEADERSHIP**

Israel Defense Forces Special Operations Detachment

Company Medical Commander / Squad Commander

UT Austin Rugby (10/2014 - 05/2015)

Events and Activities Officer

UT Austin pro-Israel advocacy organization: Texans for Israel (09/2013 – 05/2014)

VP of programming and content

# **LANGUAGES**

English Hebrew
Native or Bilingual Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

German

Limited Working Proficiency Elementary Proficiency

# **INTERESTS**

French

